Jeff Whitehead

8703 Driftwood Dr. College Station, TX 77845 (979) 219-0823

jwhitehead08@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-whitehead-530a376a/

Portfolio: https://jwhitehead08.github.io/portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/jwhitehead08

Junior web developer with a diverse entrepreneurial and business background using technology to help identify and solve business problems. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from the Coding Bootcamp at UT Austin. Leadership experience in the construction and real estate industries as well as experience founding and operating businesses.

Technical Skills

 HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Github

Experience

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

Collard Construction, Austin, TX - Project Manager

- Effectively scheduled project timelines and identified critical dates and purchase schedules
- Identified potential problems and solutions between design and execution
- Communicated with principals and designers to inform them of progress and upcoming milestones
- Coordinated subcontractors and provided detailed account of scope of work

2016 - 2021

TMG Commercial, Austin, TX - Commercial Real Estate Agent

- Served as Sales representative for developer of multiple residential developments in the greater Austin area and creatively developed marketing materials and advertising campaigns;
- Successfully represented over \$6mil in sales
- Negotiated and draft contracts
- Achieved Certified Negotiations Expert (CNE) Designation

Web Development Projects

- Food Junkies https://murmuring-crag-27720.herokuapp.com/
 - Social Application for posting favorite restaurants
 - o Tools: CSS, Tailwind, mySQL, Node.js, express.js, handlebars
 - Role: worked on the backend, constructing models and routes using mySQL; deployed application through Heroku
- Feels Like Films https://vtori37.github.io/Group-Project-1/
 - Web Application for getting movie recommendations based on your local weather
 - o Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Materialize
 - Role: Worked on the backend javascript to utilize the One Call weather
 API based on the user's geographic location

Education

2022

The Coding Bootcamp of University of Texas, Austin Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

2004 - 2008

Texas A&M University, College Station, TX *B.S. Wildlife Biology*